Let's learn how to make a pleated skirt
Open the bag skirt made in the previous video
First of all, if you want to make a pleated skirt, you have to remove the gap on the back piece
Because in the end we will form a lot of folds in the vertical direction
It is difficult to adjust the gap
Here we select this point and delete it
And delete all the extra points
After deleting, we can't simulate it directly
Because here we need to delete the pleated line that was saved before
And the pleated line of the waist
Because now our version has been modified
After that, we will re-create the pleated line
Here I use the free pleating tool
First sew the front here
Then when sewing the back piece, we should pay attention
This is the back piece here
Because we just saved it and it was dug out
So here we are almost going to remove about 30mm
Because the side will be pulled up later
So our side curve is a little bit wrong
It doesn't matter
Then use the free pleating tool to sew the back piece to the belt
After sewing, return the belt
Then simulate it together
The simulation is just to make them more flat
After adjusting the position of the pleated line
We can re-roll the belt
Because we won't change it later
In addition, before we make the pleated line
We need to turn the panel into a longer panel first
After selecting these two panels
Drag the selection box to lengthen them
In the process of lengthening, right-click can be entered
Enter the specific percentage
After opening the simulation
It becomes a long pleated skirt
Then we can use the edit panel tool
Select these lines on the side
Then open their elasticity
After opening the elasticity, this edge will shrink
We set its ratio to 60
Because it was pulled up 150% before
Now if you shrink it by 60%
It will return to the same length as before
Turn the panel manually
After turning it on
We first reduce the particle diameter and the conflict thickness
After opening the simulation
You will see that there are many pleats
After lowering
The next step is to adjust the fabric properties
First, if you don't think the pleats are obvious enough
We can increase its finelining strength
There is also the strength of the foot line
These values are adjusted to a certain degree
If the foot line is too high
The fabric will not stretch easily
Therefore, the pleats will be more obvious
After adjusting
We open the simulation
You will find that there are many pleats of sound
There is another way to make the pleats look more obvious
We can reduce the bend strength
Because after reducing the bend strength in three directions
The whole pleat property will become softer
Its pleats will be thinner
It looks more obvious
Here I choose to reduce the bend strength
Because I think these pleats are already OK
And now the pleats are not smooth enough
So we have to continue to reduce the particle diameter
Here I have reduced it to 8
In addition
If we want to make its pleats more dense
We can reduce the elasticity on the side a little more
The elasticity ratio is reduced to 50
Then simulate again
Look at me
The pleats are more dense
Finally, because the whole skirt is one
So let's combine the front and the back
And then after making the front and the back
Activate the belt and simulate
If you directly activate the simulation
Then we will find
Because there is elasticity on the side
It will shrink to the middle
So the belt will be pulled up by it
And then the belt will be stretched
Here we have to copy a fabric
The fabric copied
Use it on the belt
Then click on the browse next to it
We found Trim Fusible Rigid
This fabric
Use it
After using it
Because of this fabric
It is not easy to be stretched
So it won't be affected by elasticity
After using this fabric
It may not be very sweet
Then we can adjust the belt a little narrower
Finally, if the conditions allow
We can reduce the strength of the pleats to 5 or 3
It can make the pleats more smooth
After we have learned how to make a pleats skirt
We will try a more difficult one
Slant pleats skirt
First of all, open the previously saved pleats skirt
Then merge the front and the middle
After merging
Select this open line
Delete this line
Then delete the remaining points
After deleting, select the front
Then cut a layer to the outside
After cutting out, cancel the connection
Now we have two pleats together
But we are going to delete
The whole circle of the lining that automatically forms the outer circle
After deleting
We first need to determine the shape of the entire skirt
Because we only have a slanted pleats on the side
So at the top
We still use the lining tool to sew them together
After sewing
Pay attention to change its lining type to TURN
Because they are in and out layers
So the lining in the middle should be set to TURN
Then we use the free lining to sew the left side together
After sewing
Their lining type should also be changed to TURN
Because they are still stacked together
After fixing the left side
We can do the right side first
First of all
The outer layer of this line
The whole selection on the side
Then it is only a small section of the inner side
After sewing
We can freeze
The inner layers that can not be used
After freezing
We can select the outer layer
Press SHIFT Q
See if it is all frozen
After freezing
Open the simulation
It is a slanted pleat
Then we can combine the inner layers
Simulate with it
You can apply similar tasks to the upper layers
Open the simulation
Then we just reduce the outer layer
And the conflict thickness should also be reduced a little
After lowering it
We need to simulate
We can do the same to the outer layer
And then we can make it a little bit moreloose
And then we can make it looks more stable
And then strike here
If we want to make it a little more concentrated
If you want to make it more concentrated
We can adjust this part
the length of the seam allowance
Move the bottom point up a little bit
so that the area of the seam allowance will be smaller
and the fold will be more dense
Next, let's adjust the seam allowance on the other side
Previously, we adjusted the seam allowance on the inside of this board
Now we have to turn it over
and adjust the seam allowance on this side of the board on the outside
Next, we can select the outer board
Press Shift Q to hide it
After hiding it, open the simulation
to see the effect of the simulation
Press Shift W to display all the boards
We will see that the side is twisted here
Press Ctrl C to return to the previous
Next, let's check the error of the seam allowance
First of all, now our entire back piece
is sewn together with the inner layer
The outer layer is only a small section
sewn together with the inner layer
So we are now
going to think about
whether the left side of the inner board
should not be sewn together with the back
but should be sewn together with the outer layer
So we have to delete the seam allowance
between the inner board and the back
After deleting, we simulate
After opening the simulation, we will see
that if we want both boards to remain the same,
then we should sew the sides of the outer board
and the back pieces together
After sewing, we can properly hide the outer board
to see if it is the effect we want
If we feel that the position of the seam allowance is not tight enough
we can adjust the seam allowance
Pull this short seam allowance up a little more
You must pay attention to this point, everyone.
The inner line of the seam allowance must be turned
Finally, we can manually drag the board
to make its fold distribution a little more even
Don't forget to reduce the diameter of the inner board
to 10 and the thickness to 1
Finally, the waistband and the waistband are almost the same
The waistband and the waistband are almost the same
We can see that this side is not very even
The reason is that we don't use the TURN line type here
So we use the edge sewing sewing line tool
to change the sewing line type of this side to TURN
It will be much more even
Finally, we can reduce the particle diameter to 5
so that the fold is more detailed
We are done for this video
Thank you so much for watching
I hope you enjoyed this video
Don't forget to click the like button
This helps me to complete the steps for the next video
See you next day!